(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
可愛くてごめん
作詞・作曲:shito 編曲:HoneyWorks
Kawaikute Gomen (Sorry for Being Cute)
Lyrics/Composition: shito Arrangement: HoneyWorks
私が私のこと愛して
What's wrong with me loving myself?
何が悪いの？ 嫉妬でしょうか？
Is something wrong with that? Is it jealousy?
痛いだとか変わってるとか
That I'm cringy or that I'm weird...
届きませんね そのリプライ
Those replies don't reach me at all.
大好きな お洋服
In my favorite clothes,
大好きな お化粧で
With my favorite makeup,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
Curling my usual half-twintails,
お出かけしよう
I'm heading out.
日傘持って ぼっちだって
With my parasol, even if I'm alone,
幸せだもん
I'm still happy.
チュ！ 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute.
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for even being born.
チュ！ あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being such a tease.
気になっちゃうよねごめん
I know you can't help but notice me, sorry.
チュ！ 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute.
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for putting in all the effort.
チュ！ 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious.
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having such high femininity.
むかついちゃうよね ざまあ
It's annoying, isn't it? Serves you right!
あなたはあなたのことどうぞ
You just go ahead and do you,
私に干渉しないでください
But please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど
They say birds of a feather flock together,
届きませんね その陰口
But that backbiting doesn't reach me.
お気に入りの服で
In my favorite clothes
崩せない前髪 くしでといて お出かけしよう
Comb my bangs so they don't get messy, and let's go out
軽い女 ふざけんな
Easy girl? Don't mess with me
重すぎるっつーの
I said it's too heavy
チュ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born
チュ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so calculated
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying life
チュ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃってごめん
Sorry for putting in effort
チュ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being so feminine
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまあ
It's annoying, isn't it? Serves you right
趣味の違い 変わり者と バカにされても
Even if I'm made fun of as an eccentric with different tastes
負けたくない 怖くもない あんたらごとき
I don't want to lose, and I'm not afraid of the likes of you
自分の味方は自分でありたい 一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to be my own ally, I want to cherish myself the most
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない それが私
I don't want to make myself endure unreasonable things, that's just me
チュ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born
チュ！あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so calculated
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying life
チュ！可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute
努力しちゃってごめん
Sorry for putting in effort
チュ！尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for being so feminine
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまあ
It's annoying, isn't it? Serves you right
トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ 作詞・作曲・編曲：ツミキ
Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Tsumiki
あなたにも忘れたいこと 悲しいこと あるのかしらね
I wonder if you have things you want to forget or sad things too
知らない映画なのに涙を流すのは ドラマチックが足りてないからよ
The reason I cry even though it's a movie I don't know is because there's not enough drama
そんな愚にもつかないこと くだらないこと 考えてばかりね
Always thinking about such silly and trivial things
雨が上がれば 愛もその欲も 誰かのものになるんでしょう
Once the rain stops, love and that desire will probably belong to someone else
嘘八百のファンデーションも全部 今夜はダメよ
Even the foundation of lies, all of it, tonight is no good
なぁ、一体全体どうしてどうして、なぜなぜ、ハッてんの
Hey, why on earth, why why, why why, are you staring?
不安定な勝手ならどこまでいくの
If it's an unstable selfishness, how far will it go?
あなた一切合切 放り出せばもう
If you just throw everything away...
ああ冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Oh, it's no joke, Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たって どうにもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当で メランコリーするだけ
Just being melancholy with an ambiguous truth
私を探さないで 意味提供
Don't look for me, providing meaning
はぁ、ちゃんちゃら可笑しい法度ばっかで 祝詞が響きもしないわ
Hah, with nothing but ridiculous rules, the ritual prayers don't even echo
実体のない感情放っておいたって 策略なんて会えんのになぜ
Even if you leave empty emotions alone, why can't you meet any strategies?
ああもう、懲り懲りよ。私のカットのないキスも じっと凝らして。取り繕って、綿密に書いて
Oh, I've had enough. Even my uncut kiss, stare at it. Gloss it over, write it meticulously
年中無休リップサービス どんがんかましては へきえき
Year-round lip service, blowing it up and getting fed up
どんがらがっしゃん フィードバックは 涙の目にもに
Clatter bang, the feedback is in tearful eyes too
まぁ、頭ん中ミュージックのせいで あなたの話は一向に聞き取れない
Well, because of the music in my head, I can't hear what you're saying at all
私は全うなこと言ってい、回りだす
I'm saying proper things, starting to go around
ターンテーブルで全部 忘れさせてよ
Let me forget everything on the turntable
だけど一体全体どうしてどうして、なぜなぜハッてんの
But why on earth, why why, why why are you staring?
不安定な勝手なら見えないままで
If it's an unstable selfishness, let it remain unseen
あなた一挙手一投足 食い違ってんの
Every single move of yours is inconsistent
ああ冗談じゃないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Oh, it's no joke, Tokyo Shandy Rendez-vous
その時が来たって どうにもならないぜ
Even if that time comes, nothing can be done
曖昧な本当で メランコリーするだけ
Just being melancholy with an ambiguous truth
私を今
Me, now
ホロライブカウントダウン2023、盛り上がってるー！？
Hololive Countdown 2023, are you having fun!?
いよいよ今年も、あと少し！
Finally, this year is almost over too!
あんなこと こんなこと
This and that...
いろいろあったね
So many things happened...
2023年を最後まで
Until the very end of 2023...
全力で楽しもうぜ！
Let's enjoy it with all we've got!
冗談じゃないないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
No kidding, no way, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing you can do
浮き甲斐ないわ トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
No point in floating, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
飛ばすだけ あたしと確かめ合ってイエローマジック
Just crossing, intermingle with me, Yellow Magic
愛、合、いや トウキョウ・シャンディ・ランデヴ
Love, meeting, no, Tokyo Shandy Rendezvous
その時が来たってどうにもなんないぜ
When that time comes, there's nothing you can do
曖昧な 本当なんてメランコリー
Vague truth is just melancholy
越すだけ あたしを攫らって今 Take on me
Just crossing, snatch me away now, Take on me
ちゅ、多様性。
Chu, Diversity.
我愛你 酔いが醒めない
Wo ai ni, the intoxication won't fade
我愛你 恋が醒めない
Wo ai ni, the love won't fade
我愛你 貴様のなれの果て 察して
Wo ai ni, guess what becomes of you
無問題 話してみて
No problem, try talking to me
本に耐 トラウマの味も
Endure the truth, even the taste of trauma
反対 お手お座りで
Against it, give a hand and sit
はい 補償
Yes, compensation
喉の奥がチクンチクン
A prickle in the back of my throat
僕はドクンドクン
My heart is thumping
言葉で孤独消してみせてよ
Try erasing loneliness with words
愛も恋も毒祭して
Turning love and romance into a poison festival
僕を独占して
Monopolize me
このまま中毒になるまで
Until I become addicted like this
チューしよ
Let's kiss
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero, ge-ge-gero, gero-chu
落ちたら溶ける粉々に溢れた気持ちが
The overflowing feelings will melt and shatter if I fall
たまんないでしょ
It's irresistible, isn't it?
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero, ge-ge-gero, gero-chu
ゲロゲロ 我愛你
Gero-gero, wo ai ni
無問題
No problem
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero-chu
凡時間 勝負はいつも頓珍漢
Ordinary time, the match is always nonsensical
僕に言わせりゃ珍粉漢
If you ask me, it's gibberish
混んだ最期は乱でしょ
The crowded end will be chaos, right?
もうなんか やられればいい
Somehow, it's fine to be defeated
終わんない 忘れられない
It doesn't end, I can't forget
終わんない デカときめき偏愛
It doesn't end, a huge thumping partiality
予習
Preparation
喉の奥がチクンチクン
A prickle in the back of my throat
僕はドクンドクン
My heart is thumping
心臓ごと引き摺り出してみせてよ
Try dragging out my heart and all
気持ちいいね メン臭いけど
It feels good, even though it's a bother
やっぱ 照れ臭いけど
As expected, it's embarrassing
死ぬまで忘れられないチューしよ
Let's kiss that I'll never forget until I die
狂った街は遊びで溢れる
The crazed city overflows with play
君は僕に恋してる
You're in love with me
ときめく胸に繋がるロープ引くなよ
Don't pull the rope connected to my thumping chest
行くよ
Here we go
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero, ge-ge-gero, gero-chu
マジで震えるくらいの
To the point of truly trembling
美しいでしょ
It's beautiful, isn't it?
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲ・ゲ・ゲロ ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero, ge-ge-gero, gero-chu
せーの！
One, two!
凡時間
Ordinary time
終わんない
It doesn't end
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero-chu
我愛你
Wo ai ni
無問題
No problem
ゲ・ゲ・ゲロチュー
Ge-ge-gero-chu
花の塔
Hana no Tou
君が持ってきた漫画
The manga you brought
くれた知らない名前の花
The flower with the name I didn't know you gave me
今日はまだ来ないかな
I wonder if today is still not coming
初めての感情知ってしまった
I've learned a feeling for the first time
窓に飾った絵画なぞって
Tracing the painting decorated on the window
独りで宇宙を旅して
Traveling through space alone
それだけでいいはずだったのに
That should have been enough, but...
君の手を握ってしまったら
If I take your hand
孤独を知らないこの街には
In this city that doesn't know loneliness
もう二度と帰れない
I can never return again
ことはできないのでしょう
...it's impossible, isn't it?
君が手を差し伸べた
You reached out your hand
光で影が生まれる
Shadows are born from light
歌って聴かせて この話の続き
Sing for me, the rest of this story
連れていってみたことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
誰もが声も届かない
Where no one's voice can reach
高くそびえ立った塔の上
Atop a high-towering tower
飛ばす風船葛
Releasing heartseed vines...
僕は君に笑ってほしいんだ
...I want you to smile
満たされない穴 うわべの会話や済ましたポーズで
An unfulfilled hole, with superficial conversations and cool poses...
これまで埋めてきたけど
...I've been filling it up until now
退屈な日々を蹴散らして
Kicking away the boring days
君と二人でこの街を
Together with you, in this city...
泳げたなら それは
...if we could swim, that...
どれだけ素敵なことでしょう
...would be so wonderful
出したことないほど大きな声で
With a voice louder than I've ever made
やっと君に伝わる
I'll finally reach you
いびつな暗い朝 きっとちょうどいいな
A distorted, dark morning is probably just right
世界の端と端を結んで
Tying together the ends of the world
窓に飾った絵画をなぞって
Tracing the painting decorated on the window
一人で宇宙を旅して
Traveling through space alone
それだけでも不自由ないけど
I don't feel any lack with just that, but...
僕は選んでみたいの 高鳴る心 なぞだらけの空を
I want to choose my beating heart and the sky full of mysteries
安全なループを
The safe loop...
いま書き換えて
...rewriting it right now
君の手を握ってしまったら
Once I've taken your hand
この孤独を知らないこの街には
In this city that doesn't know this loneliness...
もう二度と帰ってくる
...I suppose I can...
ことはできないのでしょう
...never return again
いくらでも迷いながら
While getting lost as much as I want
光も影も見に行こう
Let's go see both the light and the shadow
歌って聴かせて この話の続き
Sing for me, the rest of this story
連れていってみたことない星まで
Take me to a star I've never seen before
世界の端と端を結んで
Tying together the ends of the world
NEXT
もうすぐ時計は6時
The clock will soon strike six
もうそこに一番星
The first star is already there
影を踏んで夜に
Stepping on shadows...
紛れたくなる帰り道
...wanting to vanish into the night on the way home
どんなに探してみても
No matter how much I look...
一つしかない星
...there's only one star
何億光年離れた...
Billions of light-years away...
離れたところから
From a distant place
あんなに輝く
It shines so brightly
いいな 君は みんなから愛されて
How nice, you're loved by everyone
いいや 僕は ずっと一人きりさ
No, I've always been all alone
ずっと一人きりさ
Always all alone
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
星降る夜 一瞬の願い事
A night of falling stars, a momentary wish
煌めいて 揺らめいて
Sparkling, swaying
震えてるシグナル
A trembling signal
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
空見上げて指を差されるような
Like being pointed at while looking up at the sky
繋いだ線 解かないで
Don't untie the line we connected
僕がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright I am
もうすぐ時計は８時
The clock is almost at 8:00
夜空に満天の星
A night sky full of stars
何処の根 離れたところにはもう
In a place far from its roots
ないかもしれない
It might not be there anymore
月が綺麗で泣きそうになるのは
The reason I feel like crying because the moon is beautiful
泣きそうになるのは
I feel like crying
いつの日にか 別れが来るから
Is because one day, a parting will come
別れが来るから
A parting will come
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
彗星みたいに流れる独り言
A soliloquy that flows like a comet
消えたいく 残像は
The vanishing afterimage is
真夜中のプリズム
A midnight prism
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
切なる願い 誰かに届いたら
If my earnest wish reaches someone
変われるかな 夜の淵を
Could I change? Along the edge of night
なぞるような こんな僕でも
Tracing it, even someone like me
遥か彼方 僕らは出会ってしまった
In the far distance, we happened to meet
カルマだから 何度も出会ってしまうよ
Because it's karma, we'll keep meeting again and again
雲の隙間で
Through the gaps in the clouds
君と集まって星座になれたら
If I could gather with you and become a constellation
夜 広げて描こう 絵空事
Let's spread the night and draw an idle dream
暗闇を 照らすような
Like lighting up the darkness
満月じゃなくても
Even if it's not a full moon
だから集まって星座になりたい
So I want to gather and become a constellation
色とりどりの光 放つような
Like emitting multi-colored light
繋いだ線 解かないよ
I won't untie the line we connected
君がどんなに眩しくても
No matter how bright you are
第ゼロ感
Dai Zero Kan
群れをはぐれて 夢をくわえた
Wandered away from the pack, clutching a dream
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
I felt like that would be the last time
獣は砂を一握り撒いた
The beast scattered a handful of sand
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
I felt like that would be the last time
不確かな夢叶えるのさ
I'll make uncertain dreams come true
約束の夜に
On the promised night
微かな風にうねるのさ
Swaying in a faint breeze
静寂の朝に
On the silent morning
遠い星の少年は
The boy from a distant star
その腕に約束の飾り
Has the ornament of a promise on his arm
まだ旅路の最中さ
Still in the middle of a journey
幻惑の園に
In the garden of illusion
霞んで消えた 轍の先へ
Beyond the rut that faded away...
それが最後に なる気がしたんだ
I felt like that would be the end.
手負いの夢を 紡ぎ直せば
If I spin the wounded dreams again...
それが最後に なる気がしたんだ
I felt like that would be the end.
迷走前夜抗うのさ 約束の前に
I'll resist on the eve of straying, before the promise.
Woah-oh-oh-oh...
命綱はないのさ サーカスの夜に
There's no lifeline on a circus night.
Woah-oh-oh-oh...
まだ格闘の最中さ
I'm still in the middle of a struggle.
あの場所に加速する さらに
Accelerating towards that place, even further.
雨上がりのシャンデリア 幻惑の外に
A chandelier after the rain, outside the enchantment.
Woah-oh-oh-oh...
Messed up, smashed, triple trap, kill 'em in a...
大丈夫さ
It's alright.
Colors steal the sound thus...
Bask in the penetrate base, be-bap
Get triple buzz, be-bap...
Wonder buzz, must be-bap, heat check
Bask in the gamma, be-bap...
Bask in the penetrate base, be-bap...
Wonder buzz, just wonder buzz...
脳内更地に EXTRA BUZZ
EXTRA BUZZ in a brain cleared like a wasteland.
食わず嫌いに HAPPY BUZZ
HAPPY BUZZ for those with pickiness.
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
ランドリー今日はガラ空きでラッキーデー
The laundry's empty today, it's a lucky day.
かったりい油汚れもこれでバイバイ
Say bye-bye to those annoying oil stains with this.
誰だ誰だ頭の中 呼びかける声は
Who is it, who is it? The voice calling out inside my head.
あれが欲しい これが欲しいと歌っている
It's singing that it wants this and that.
幸せになりたい 楽して生きていたい
I want to be happy, I want to live an easy life.
この手につかみたい
I want to grasp it in these hands,
あなたのその胸の中
inside that chest of yours.
ハッピーで埋め尽くして レストインピースまで行こうぜ
Fill it all up with happy, let's go until we rest in peace.
いつかみた地獄もいいところ 愛をばらまいて
Even that hell I saw once is a nice place, scattering love around.
アイラブユー貶してくれ 全部奪って笑ってくれマイハニー
I love you, disparage me, take it all and laugh for me, my honey.
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
なんか忘れちゃってんだ
I've forgotten something.
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
三番線ホームから
From platform number three
ずれ落ちる足元
My feet slip
ハングリーこじらせて
Worsening my hunger
吐きそうな人生
A life that makes me want to vomit
止まない雨はないよりさきに
Before saying "no rain lasts forever"
その傘をくれよ
Give me that umbrella
あれが欲しい これが欲しい
I want that, I want this
全て欲しいと言ったら嬉しい？
Would you be happy if I said I want it all?
幸せになりたい
I want to be happy
楽して生きていたい
I want to live an easy life
全部めちゃくちゃにしたい
I want to mess everything up
何もかも消し去りたい
I want to wipe everything away
あなたのその胸の中
Deep inside your heart
Rest In Peace まで行こうぜ
Let's go until Rest In Peace
もう一個だけ迎える天国じゃ
In the heaven we'll one day reach
どうも居心地悪い
I won't feel at home there at all
奪い返して 奪い取って
Reclaim it, seize it
笑ってくれマイハニー
Smile for me, my honey
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
なんかすごい良い感じ
Feeling pretty great
HAPPY LUCKY こんにちはBABY
HAPPY LUCKY Hello, BABY
もう一個だけいたい そりゃつまらない
I want to be here just a bit longer, it's boring otherwise
HAPPY LUCKY こんにちはBABY
HAPPY LUCKY Hello, BABY
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
なんかすごい良い感じ
Feeling pretty great
努力 未来 A BEAUTIFUL STAR
Effort, future, A BEAUTIFUL STAR
NEXT
本当は分かってた
To be honest, I knew
いけないことだったって分かってたのに
I knew it was something I shouldn't do, yet...
この手をすり抜ける全部が愛に見えたの
Everything slipping through my fingers looked like love
確かめていた言葉が形になって揺れるだけ
The words I was confirming just take shape and sway
弾いて描いて きっとそれだけ
Typing it out, that must be all
つまらないな 世界の読み合わせ
How boring, the world's proofreading
あとちょっとね 分かりかけてたのに
Just a little more, I was starting to understand, yet...
脳に這入って 全部忘れちゃえ
Enter my brain, and forget everything
数センチの熱を読み合わせ
Reading the heat of a few centimeters
見つめ合えたら
If we can look into each other's eyes
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
やるせない日々 解像度の悪い夢を見たい
Helpless days, I want to see low-resolution dreams
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
甘いハッタリ Don't stop the music darling
Sweet bluffing, don't stop the music darling
本当に分かってる？
Do you really understand?
いけないことだったって分かってる
I know it was something I shouldn't do
多分
Maybe
時間だけが過ぎてく温度に満ちていく
Only time passes, filling up with temperature
言い訳してる 間もなく
Making excuses, before long
裸になってしまうだけ
I'll just end up naked
きっと溜まっていくんだ ずっと
It'll surely keep accumulating, forever
終わってしまえばいいと ふっと
Thinking it'd be fine if it just ended, suddenly
傷んで腐っていく あの甘い果実のように
Bruising and rotting, like that sweet fruit
僕ら壊れていく
We are breaking down
だから
So
酔って舞って 全部忘れちゃえ
Get drunk and dance, forget everything
そうかもね 隣り合わせ
Maybe so, side-by-side
見つめ合えたら
If we can look into each other's eyes
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
分かりたいのに 変にまどろっこしい嘘が嫌い
I want to understand, yet I hate awkwardly tedious lies
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
分かりたいのに
Even though I want to understand
Two step from hell my darling
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
やるせない日々 解像度の悪い夢を見たい
Helpless days, I want to see low-resolution dreams
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
甘いハッタリ Don't stop the music darling
Sweet bluffing, don't stop the music darling
Overdose 君とふたり
Overdose, just the two of us
分からないけど
I don't know, but...
変に今を煽り
Stirring up the present in a strange way
嘘でもいいから
Even if it's a lie
どっか遠く君と二人
Somewhere far away, just the two of us
甘いハッタリ
A sweet bluff
Don't stop the music, darling
凍りついた心には太陽を
A sun for a frozen heart
そして僕が君にとってそのポジションを
And I want to be that for you
そんなだいぶ傲慢な思い込みを
An assumption quite arrogant like that
こじらせてたんだよ ごめんね
I've made it complicated, I'm sorry
笑ってやって
Please laugh at it
火傷しそうなほどのポジティブの
Of a positivity so hot it might burn
冷たさと残酷さに気付いたんだよ
I noticed its coldness and cruelty
きっと君に渡したいものは
Surely, what I want to give you is
もっとひんやり熱いもの
Something more coolly hot
綺麗事じゃないけど 綺麗で揺るぎないもの
Not just lip service, but something beautiful and unwavering
上辺よりも胸の奥の奥を温めるもの
Something that warms deep within the heart rather than the surface
理想だけはあるけど
I only have ideals, but
心のどこ探しても まるで見つからないんだよ
No matter where I look in my heart, I can't find them at all
伝えたい 伝わらない その不条理が今
I want to tell you, but it's not getting through; that absurdity is now
きつく縛りつけるんだよ
Binding me so tightly
臆病な僕の
Of my cowardly self
この一挙手一投足を
Every single move I make
言葉はまるで雪の結晶 君にプレゼントしたくても
Words are like snowflakes, even if I want to present them to you
夢中になればなるほどに 形は崩れ落ちて溶けていって
The more absorbed I become, the more they crumble and melt away
消えてしまうけど
And they disappear, but
でも僕が選ぶ言葉が そこに託された思いが
But the words I choose, the feelings entrusted to them
君の胸を震わすのを 諦められない
I can't give up on making your heart tremble
「愛してる」よりも愛が届くまで
Until a love greater than "I love you" reaches you
もう少しだけ待ってて
Wait just a little longer
薄すぎてただそばに立ってても
Even if I'm just standing by your side
不必要に汗をかいてしまう僕なんかもう
Someone like me who breaks into an unnecessary sweat
どうしたって生温くて君を痛めつけてしまうのだろう
No matter what, I'm lukewarm and probably end up hurting you
手のひらが熱いほど心は冷たいんでしょう
The hotter the palms, the colder the heart must be, right?
冗談でもそんな残酷なこと言わないでよ
Don't say such cruel things, even as a joke
別にいいんだけど
I don't really mind, but
全人生をかけても ちゃんと覆させてよ
Even if it takes my whole life, let me properly prove you wrong
救いたい 救われたい このイコ一ルが今
I want to save, I want to be saved; this equation is now
優しく剥がしていくんだよ
Gently peeling away
堅い論理 武装
Hard logical armor
プライドの過剰包装を
Excessive packaging of pride
正しさよりも優しさが欲しい
I want kindness more than correctness
そしてそれを受け取れるのは イルミネーションみたいな
And the only one who can receive it is like an illumination
不特定多数じゃなくて ただ一人 君であってほしい
Not one of the unspecified many, but you and only you
かじかんだ言葉で 荒れた日々を直そうとして
Trying to fix the stormy days with numb words
過信しすぎた熱量で 引かれてしまったカ一テン
The curtains that were drawn due to overconfident heat
そんな失敗作を
Such a failure
重ねて 重ねて 重ねて 見つけたいんだいつか
I want to find it someday, piling them up, again and again
最高の正解と言える僕を
The me that can be called the best answer
言葉はまるで雪の結晶 君にプレゼントしたとして
Suppose I presented words to you like snowflakes
時間が経ってしまえば大抵 記憶からこぼれ落ちて溶けていって
After some time passes, they usually spill from memory and melt away
消えてしまうけど
And they disappear, but
絶えず僕らのスト一リ一に 添えられた字幕のように
Like the subtitles constantly added to our story
思い返した時
When looking back
ふいに目をやる時に 君の胸を震わすもの
Something that makes your heart tremble when you suddenly glance at it
探し続けたい 愛してるよりも愛が届くまで
I want to keep searching until a love greater than "I love you" reaches you
愛がドグマまで
Love to the point of dogma
もう少しだけ待ってて
Please wait just a little longer
言葉など何も欲しくないほど
To the point where I don't want any words
悲しみに凍てつく夜でも
Even on nights frozen with sadness
勝手に君のそばで
Selfishly, by your side
あれこれと考えてる
I'm thinking about this and that
雪が溶けても残ってる
Even if the snow melts, it remains
オトナブルー
Otona Blue
わかってる 欲しいんでしょ？
I know, you want it, don't you?
艶やかなこの唇
These glossy lips
柔らかいとこたち引き寄せる
Luring in the soft parts
息を飲むほど甘い蜜
Sweet nectar that makes you catch your breath
わかってる 欲しいんでしょ？
I know, you want it, don't you?
二度見するこの体
This body that makes you look twice
朝晩町一人歩けば
Walking alone in town morning and night
破廉恥な視線が絡みつくね
Shameless gazes entwine around me
何を期待してるの？
What are you expecting?
そのうちじゃなくて今すぐがいいの
Not 'eventually,' I want it right now
大人の恋に焦がれて
Yearning for an adult love
見た目よりも残るあどけない
More innocent than I look
心だけが先走る
Only my heart is rushing ahead
青い蕾のまま
Still a blue bud
オトナブルー
Otona Blue
わかってる 欲しいんでしょ？
I know, you want it, don't you?
刺激する私のすべて
Stimulating everything about me
その谷間まで魅了する
Fascinating even the cleavage
いつかは花になるアマリリス
Someday I'll become a flower, an amaryllis
優しいだけの言葉じゃなくて
Not just kind words
心で繋がりたくて
I want to be connected by our hearts
ありきたりなメイクじゃ隠せない
Common makeup can't hide it
ただ憧れてた
I was just longing for it
夢を見る
Dreaming
あなたの前でまた
Before you once again
オトナブルー
Otona Blue
そのうちじゃなくて今すぐがいいの
Not 'eventually,' I want it right now
大人の恋に焦がれて
Yearning for an adult love
見た目よりも残るあどけない
More innocent than I look
気持ちだけが空回り
Only my feelings are spinning in circles
私を見つけて
Find me
優しいだけの言葉じゃなくて
Not just kind words
心で繋がりたくて
I want to be connected by our hearts
ありきたりなメイクじゃ隠せない
Common makeup can't hide it
ただ憧れてた
I was just longing for it
夢を見る
Dreaming
まだ見ぬ恋路を
A love path not yet seen
追いかけて
Chasing after
オトナブルー
Otona Blue
外出た瞬間 終わったわ
The moment I stepped outside, it was over
強風オールバック
Strong Wind All-Back
天気はいいのに進めない
The weather is good, but I can't move forward
風強すぎて お腹なり
The wind is too strong, and my stomach is growling
定期的にオールバック
Regularly an all-back
地下に潜りたいな
I want to dive underground
って思いました
...is what I thought.
観察者へ なくなれば
To the observers, if I disappear...
あったかいのに
...even though it's warm.
ずっと座りたいな
I want to keep sitting forever.
って思いました
...is what I thought.
いないいない と外出たら
I thought I was safe, but when I stepped outside...
ハトハトハトハト 大乱舞
Pigeons, pigeons, pigeons, pigeons, a wild dance!
あ、ちょっと出た瞬間終わったわ
Ah, the moment I stepped out, it was over.
天気はいいのに進めない
The weather is nice, but I can't move forward.
風強すぎてお亡くなり
The wind is too strong, I'm done for.
定期定期的にオールバック
My hair keeps getting blown back periodically.
今年もみんなありがとう！
Thank you everyone for this year too!
来年のホロライブも勢いは
Next year's Hololive's momentum too...
止まらねーぜ！
...won't stop!
あ、ちょっと出た瞬間終わったわ
Ah, the moment I stepped out, it was over.
天気はいいのに進めない
The weather is nice, but I can't move forward.
風強すぎてお亡くなり
The wind is too strong, I'm done for.
定期定期的にオールバック
My hair keeps getting blown back periodically.
ちょっと出た瞬間終わったわ
The moment I stepped out, it was over.
天気はいいのに進めない
The weather is nice, but I can't move forward.
風強すぎてお亡くなり
The wind is too strong, I'm done for.
定期定期的にオールバック
My hair keeps getting blown back periodically.
髪の毛 強風 オールバック
Hair, strong wind, all back.
無敵の笑顔で荒らすメディア
Shaking up the media with an invincible smile,
知りたいその秘密ミステリアス
I want to know that secret, it's so mysterious.
抜けてるとこさえ彼女のエリア
Even her flaws are part of her territory,
完璧で嘘つきな君は
A perfect, lying version of you...
天才的なアイドル様
...is a genius idol.
今日何食べた？
What did you eat today?
好きな本は？
What's your favorite book?
遊びに行くならどこに行くの？
If you go out to play, where would you go?
何も食べてない
I haven't eaten anything.
それは内緒
That's a secret.
何を聴かれてものらりくらり
No matter what I'm asked, I'll dodge the question.
そう淡々と
So nonchalantly,
だけど燦々と
yet brilliantly.
見えそうで見えない秘密は蜜の味
A secret that's almost visible is the taste of honey.
あれもないないない
That's not it, no, no.
これもないないない
This isn't it either, no, no.
好きなタイプは？
What's your type?
相手は？さあ答えて
Who is it? Come on, answer.
誰かを好きになることなんて私分からなくてさ
I don't really understand what it's like to love someone.
嘘か本当か知り得ない
Whether it's a lie or the truth, I can't tell.
そんな言葉にまた一人堕ちる
One by one, they fall for those words.
また好きにさせる
Making them fall in love again.
誰もが目を奪われていく
Everyone's gaze is captured.
君は完璧で究極のアイドル
You are the perfect and ultimate idol.
金際現れない
The kind that will never appear again,
一番星の生まれ変わり
the reincarnation of the brightest star.
その笑顔で愛してるで
With that smile, with that 'I love you',
誰も彼も虜にしていく
you captivate everyone.
その瞳がその言葉が
Those eyes, those words...
嘘でもそれは完全なアイ
even if they're lies, they're perfect love.
はいはいあの子は特別です
Yes, yes, that girl is special.
我々は鼻からおまけです
We're just extras from the start.
お星様の引き立て役Bです
We're just the background dancers for the star.
全てがあの子のおかげなわけ
Everything is thanks to her...
ない、洒落臭い 妬み嫉妬なんてないわけがない
Not! How annoying. There's no way I don't feel envy and jealousy.
これはネタじゃないからこそ許せない
This isn't just a joke, that's why it's unforgivable.
完璧じゃない君じゃ許せない
I can't forgive you if you're not perfect.
自分を許せない
I can't forgive myself.
誰よりも強い君以外は認めない
I won't acknowledge anyone but the strongest you.
誰もが信じあがめてる
Everyone believes in and worships you.
まさに最強で無敵のアイドル
Truly the strongest and invincible idol.
弱点なんて見当たらない
No weaknesses to be found.
一番星を宿している
Possessing the light of the brightest star.
弱いとこなんて見せちゃダメダメ
You must never show your weaknesses.
知りたくないとこは見せずに
Don't show anything they don't want to see.
唯一無二じゃなくちゃイヤイヤ
You have to be one of a kind, no exceptions.
それこそ本物のアイ
That's what true love is.
得意の笑顔で沸かすメディア
Firing up the media with her signature smile,
隠しきるこの秘密だけは
hiding away this secret alone.
愛してるって嘘で積むキャリア
Building a career on the lie of 'I love you'.
これこそ私なりの愛だ
This is my own kind of love.
流れる汗も綺麗なアクア
Even the flowing sweat is a beautiful aqua,
ルビーを隠したこの瞼
with ruby hidden behind these eyelids.
歌い踊り舞う私はマリア
Singing and dancing, I am Maria.
そう嘘はとびきりの愛だ
Yes, lies are the ultimate form of love.
誰かに愛されたことも
I've never been loved by anyone,
誰かのこと愛したこともない
nor have I ever loved anyone.
そんな私の嘘がいつか本当になること
But I hope that one day, my lie will become the truth.
信じてる
I believe in that.
いつかきっと全部手に入れる
I'll surely get everything one day.
私はそう欲張りなアイドル
I'm such a greedy idol.
等身大でみんなのこと
I want to love everyone properly,
ちゃんと愛したいから
just as I am.
今日も嘘をつくの
That's why I'll lie again today.
この言葉がいつか本当になる日を願って
Hoping that these words will one day become the truth.
それでもまだ
But even so...
君と君にだけは言えてない
...I haven't been able to say it to you two.
見せずに…痛いけど…
Without showing… it hurts, but…
あ、やっと言えた
Ah, I finally said it
これは絶対嘘じゃない
This is definitely not a lie
愛してる
I love you
あ、あ、聞こえてますか？
Ah, ah, can you hear me?
こちらステージから離れて、じゃーん！楽屋に来てます！
I'm away from the stage and, ta-da! I'm in the green room!
あ、ちょっと待ってね！
Ah, wait a second!
どうすか？今の気持ちどうすか？
How is it? How do you feel right now?
そら先輩、着替えるから、ちょっと待ってください。
Sora-senpai is changing, so please wait a bit.
どうすか？今の気持ちどうすか？
How is it? How do you feel right now?
日本語が通じない、聞き分けの悪い子ですね。
You don't understand Japanese? What a stubborn kid.
悪い子はお仕置きだよ。
Bad kids get punished.
やっちゃってくださいよ！
Go for it!
我、総帥だぞ！
I'm the Commander-in-Chief!
こっちゃ悪魔と天使のハーフだぞ！
I'm a half-demon, half-angel!
そんでこっちは番長だぞ！
And I'm the leader!
大人しくおねんねしなさい！
Sit down and go to sleep!
じゃ、変わって次の楽屋見てみましょうか。
Now, let's look at the next room.
こんにちは…うわ、風っすよ！
Hello… Whoa, it's windy!
何でこの楽屋だけこんな暴風？！
Why is there such a storm in only this room?!
はー！風に飛ぶ！飛ぶ！
Hah! I'm flying in the wind! I'm flying!
事件の匂いがする。アメの出番かな？
I smell an incident. Is it Ame's turn?
楽屋で強風の疑い さくらみこ容疑者を逮捕
Arrested for suspicion of strong wind in the green room: Suspect Sakura Miko
みこじゃない、やってない！
It's not Miko! I didn't do it!
何で私まで？！
Why am I involved too?!
おー、先輩たちはどうやら捕まってしまいましたね。
Oh, it seems the seniors got caught.
他の楽屋は…うわ、酒臭い。
The next room is… Wow, it smells like booze.
景気の一杯じゃい！
A refreshing drink!
ラミィの酒が飲めねえってか？！
You're saying you can't drink Lamy's sake?!
もう飲めねえっす…もう…
I can't drink anymore... No more...
ライブ中なのに出来上がってますね。
Even though it's before the live, they're already drunk.
締めはラーメンっしょ。心のエキスが効いてるね。
The finish is ramen. The essence of the heart is working.
出しにしないで！
Don't make me into soup!
隠し味が足りねえよな。
Not enough secret flavor.
刺激も足りませんね。
Not enough spice.
具も足りねえな。
Not enough ingredients.
二軒目行くか！
Let's go to the next place!
あ、お客さん、お代がまだだよ。
Ah, customer, you haven't paid yet.
酒臭くてたまらないね。次の部屋に行きましょう。
It's so smelly. Let's go to the next room.
何か美味しそうな匂いがしますね。
I smell something delicious.
美味しいね。美味しい。
It's delicious. So delicious.
何でお前はこんなに美味しいんだ？
Why are you so delicious?
どんどん焼こう、どんどん！
Keep grilling, more and more!
仲間をたべられてますが、今の気持ちはどうですか？
Your friends are being eaten, but how do you feel?
こわ！美味しいなら、それでよし。
Scary! If it's delicious, then it's fine.
う！からしが入ってる！
Mm! There's mustard inside!
からし食べました！
I ate the mustard!
インドネシアが入ってる！
There's Indonesia inside!
これ、ビジネスチャンスかも。色んな味を堪能してね。
This might be a business opportunity. Enjoy the various flavors.
タコパって感じね。では、次の部屋に行きましょう！
It's like a Takoyaki party. Now, on to the next room!
突撃インタビュー！メルちゃん！
Surprise interview! Mel-chan!
お、打ち上げ会？
Whoa, the after-party?
突撃インタビューね。
Surprise interview.
お、打ち上げ会？
Oh, is it the after-party?
インタビューね。
Interview.
えーと…えーと…
Um... um...
無理にボケなくていいからね。
You don't have to force a joke.
え、メルたちの歌、聴いてくれました？このあとも楽しんでってね。
Uh, did you listen to our song? Enjoy the rest of the show!
おいら凄く楽しみです。
I'm really looking forward to it.
ねえ、なんかおかゆも喋ってよ。
Hey, Okayu-u, say something too.
ニョンギ！
Nyongi!
どうですか？
How is it?
え、何が？
Eh, what?
いや、なんかインタビューしろって言われて。どうですか？
Well, I was told to interview someone. How is it?
どうですか？って、ちょ、マイク近いから！何で鋭利なんですか？！
“How is it?” Hey, the mic is too close! Why is it so sharp?!
どうですか？面白いですか？！
How is it? Is it fun?!
無量大数で喋らせろよ！
Let me speak in infinite numbers!
とのことでした。じゃ、バトンタッチ！
That was it. Now, baton touch!
はい！次は私たちがインタビューするよ。
Yes! Next, we’ll be interviewing.
こんばんは！楽屋突撃インタビューです。
Good evening! It's the backstage surprise interview.
もうすぐ2023年も終わりますね。
2023 is almost over.
本当あっという間。もうすぐ年明け！
It really went by so fast. New Year's is coming soon!
インドネシアって時差どれくらいあるの？
How much time difference is there in Indonesia?
インドネシアの年明けは2時間後かな。
Indonesian New Year is probably 2 hours later.
二回お祝いできますね。
We can celebrate twice.
お、なんかいいね、その考え方。
Oh, that’s a good way to think about it.
カウントダウンまであとどれくらいだろう？
I wonder how long until the countdown?
あ、やばい、次いかなきゃ！
Ah, oh no, we have to go to the next one!
それでは、次のインタビューは大神ミオ先輩！よろしく頑張るぞ！
Now, the next interviewer is Mio-senpai! Good luck!
次は、こちらの楽屋！
Next is this room!
おるるるるる。この先は我々ホロのグラフィティが乗っ取らせてもらうぜ！
Orurururu. From here on, we, Holo no Graffiti, are taking over!
返して！戻して！俺たちが何したって言うんだ！
Give it back! Put it back! What did we even do?!
ぐだぐだ言うな、年越すぞ。
Don't complain. It's New Year's Eve.
こんなはちゃめちゃ空間で年越したくない！！！
I don't want to spend New Year's in this chaotic space!!!
へっ、だったら止めてみろ。
Heh, then try to stop us.
ブラウザバックするわ。低評価で。
I'm going to browser back. With a dislike.
うちの番だけ大外れ。
Only my turn was a total failure.
なんかトラブルがあったみたいで。彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！アイドルVTuberの星街すいせいです！
Seems like there was some trouble. The comet-like star in the rough! Idol VTuber Hoshimachi Suisei!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
すいちゃーん！
Sui-chaan!
ねずみ小僧の顎が外れた！
The mouse kid's jaw came off!
この顎でカウントダウンできるわ！
I can do the countdown with this jaw!
とにかく食ってやるしかないかも。
Anyway, we just have to eat it.
なんでそこで私を見るの？
Why are you looking at me?
すいちゃんなら、躊躇なく渾身の力でやるかなって。
I thought Sui-chan would do it with full power without hesitation.
食らえお前ら！
Eat this, you guys!
仕方ないな。
Can't be helped.
ネズミ捕り仕掛けにほいほい。きゃー！
The mouse trap is set. Kyaa!
じゃ、次の楽屋行きます！
Okay, on to the next room!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
にょにょにょにょ、ふんっ！
Nyon-nyon-nyon... hmph!
あいつは魔法の過剰摂取で沸点がパンになったんや
She had a magic overdose and her boiling point turned to bread.
お前も食らえー！
Take this, too!
こぼも！こぼも！
Kobo too! Kobo too!
何このガキ、ガキには早いんだよなー
What a brat. It's too early for kids.
己もガキやろがい！
You're a kid yourself!
ガキって言った方がガキなんですー
The one who says "kid" is the kid.
あっ、危ない！
Ah, look out!
うわああああ！
Waaaaah!
ちぇー、もうつまんない！
Che... This is boring now!
次の楽屋行こ！
Let's go to the next dressing room!
お邪魔ー！
Excuse me!
赤たんが寝てる最中でしょうが！
The baby is trying to sleep!
アンキモなのに起きちまったのだな
Even though I'm Ankimo, I've woken up.
私たちも寝ましょうか？お父さん。
Shall we sleep too, Father?
誰がお父さんだ！
Who are you calling "Father"?!
こぼも寝る、こぼも！
Kobo's gonna sleep too!
しょうがないなー、お父様が寝かしつけてあげよう
Fine, then Father will put you to sleep.
僕もご一緒していいかな？
May I join you?
母さん、あの男は誰だい！
Mother, who is that man?!
違うのよ、違うのよ！
It's not what you think!
赤たんの芝居にも疲れちまったよ
I'm tired of acting like a baby.
じゃ、ママがマイク代わるわね
Then Mama will take over the mic.
次の楽屋はこちらでーす！
The next dressing room is this way!
こんばんはー！
Good evening!
いやああああ！
Aaaaah!
ノエル先輩が回りすぎて止まりませーん！
Noel-senpai is spinning too much and won't stop!
止まらねー！
She won't stop!
と、とりあえずインタビューを...
Anyway, let's start the interview...
マイクが！
The mic!
この状況でインタビューは無理です！
An interview is impossible in this situation!
チョコ先生も手伝って！
Choco-sensei, help us out!
じゃバトンタッチしちゃう
Then I'll pass the baton.
あやめ様、手伝って！
Ayame-sama, help us!
あやめ様ー！
Ayame-sama!
可愛くなくてごめん...
I'm sorry for not being cute...
いつも暗くて...
Always gloomy...
可愛くなくてごめん...
I'm sorry for not being cute...
シャークで...
Just a shark...
可愛くなくてごめん...
I'm sorry for not being cute...
うつむきで...
Head hung low...
あたま反動がこんなところに
The mental backlash is showing here.
まだまだこれからステージあるのに
We still have stages to go after this,
やめてくださいそのテンション
so please stop that mood.
あれ？ぺこら先輩は感動ないでござるか？
Huh? Pekora-senpai, aren't you moved?
可愛くてごめん！
Sorry for being cute!
このうさぎ自己肯定感高っ！
This rabbit has such high self-esteem!
これこれ、みんな可愛いよー
Now now, everyone's cute.
それではー！
And now!
あー、そんなこんなで...
Ah, and just like that...
あと数十秒で年越しだー！
In just a few dozen seconds, it'll be the new year!
いやー、長いようで短かったですねー
Well, it felt long yet short at the same time.
来年ももっともっともっと！
Next year, even more and more and more!
みんなと一緒に！
Together with everyone!
ほら！
Look!
みんな屋上に集まれー！
Everyone, gather on the rooftop!
10! 9! 8! 7! 6! 5! 4! 3! 2! 1! 0!
ハッピーニューイヤー！
HAPPY NEW YEAR!
Everything is gonna be alright
感じよう今 噂の feeling too
Feel it now, that rumored feeling too
Are you ready? コンコンコン
Are you ready? Kon kon kon
Yes このキツネに化かされて
Yes, be bewitched by this fox
Knock knock knock 心を開けて
Knock knock knock, open up your heart
Uu ya yeah Everything is gonna be alright
感じよう今 噂の feeling too
Feel it now, that rumored feeling too
Wow wow wow コンコンコン 魔法をかけて
Wow wow wow, kon kon kon, cast a spell on you
Uh baby 朝まで feeling too
Uh baby, that feeling too until morning
しんちまいひいてよ My Holy
Shinchimai hiite yo My Holy
あーまたたきはこえが きつきひびく
Ah, the twinkling voices resonate strongly
連なり朽ち 金の泥 群れ 共に嘆く夜
Decaying in succession, golden mud, a crowd, a night of shared lament
どうか宙 伝播する想い
Please, let my feelings propagate through space
今を澄ます 約する
I'll clear the present, I promise
誇りと 隣に君がいるから 私は迷わない
With pride, and because you're by my side, I won't lose my way
光咲き満ちて
Light blooming in full
This is my Holy
闇に紛れ　甘いトコに溶けて
Blending into the darkness, melting into a sweet spot
くたびれた鎖　繋いでは　ほどいて
Connecting and unravelling tired chains
光の姿　化けて　瞳汚して
Taking the form of light, tainting your eyes
鈍色の毒が　いたむのね
The leaden poison is painful, isn't it?
ギラギラ　響かせてギラ
Make it glitter, let it ring out, glitter
ギラギラよ　ハッハッ
Glittering, ha-ha
とどかせてギラ　ギラギラ
Make it reach, glitter, glitter
鳴らせよギラ　闇をとき放ちか
Sound it out, glitter, release the darkness
ヤムノカ　サキカ
Will you fall ill, or will you bloom?
噛みつきはしないわ
I won't bite you
なぐさめもしないわ
I won't comfort you either
私のものになれ
Become mine
飽きたら　のり捨て
I'll discard you once I'm bored
ポポポポポポポポ
Po po po po po po po po
ネネネネネネネネ
Ne ne ne ne ne ne ne ne
ポポネネネネポポ
Po po ne ne ne ne po po
Baby, hold your light. Are you living free?
Let’s forget everything and have some fun!
3, 2, 1!
Give you all a sweet surprise, hear me testify
Baby, Baby, Destiny Nothing's Ordinary
Give it all, give it heart, give it all for life
Keep on giving in, go show them your best try
Once you've start, there is no more going back
What you doing, Rat? Show them all your luck!
5, 4, 3, 2, 1, Bingo!
Hear me out, baby! Baby don't care
Hear me out, baby!
Now sing it baby
ラブラブラブラブラ
Love love love love love
LOVE, HATE, OR THE SAME? IF YOU KNOW, PLAY THE GAME
I’M LACK OF POP AND PSYCH-OUT,
I CAN’T WIPE OUT THE FINGER ON THE WATER
LOVE, HATE, OR THE SAME? IF YOU KNOW, PLAY THE GAME
HELP ME OUT, DECIDE IF YOU WANT ME TO SHUT THE LINE
LOVE IS JUST A GIVE-IT-UP GAME,
LOVE HATE IS A SAME BALL
TOUCH ME LIKE A FLAME, I’M AN ABLE PLAY THE SAME BALL
DO YOU, DO YOU, DO YOU FEEL LIKE JUST A GAME?
LOVE IS JUST A GIVE-IT-UP GAME,
LOVE HATE IS A SAME BALL
Hey!
ただただ回れ　黙り黙り前を
Just keep spinning, silently looking ahead
言えないね　そんな強い言葉は
I can't say it, such strong words
少しだけ静かにしてほしいね
I want you to be a little quiet
私たち退避網
The two of us are contrasting
今の今みたいなはずだったのに
It was supposed to be just like now
セカイ点々点　ボクヤヤヤヤ
World dot-dot-dot, I am...
見やるその日までは　ソトトトトト
Until the day I see it...
イェイ　今夜の事には
Yei, tonight's matter is...
街点々点チャチャチャ　あなたの街中
City dot-dot-dot, cha cha cha, in your city
建て直すわ　バテサ
I'll rebuild it...
点々々々　ボクヤヤヤヤ
Dot-dot-dot-dot, I am...
果たすその日まで　レレレトトト
Until the day it's fulfilled...
点点々々々々々
Dot-dot-dot-dot...
FUSAE! LELIA! FEE!
ZETA! BILKYO! DEFIS!
海が揺れる夜　波に映った星
Stars reflected in the waves on a night when the sea sways
光った月が
The shining moon...
...消えてゆく
...disappearing
指先でゆらゆらと
Swaying at the fingertips
その腕で
In those arms
止まった時計の
The hands of the clock
針に踏み込んだ
That stopped, I stepped in
雲が描いた列車
The train drawn by the clouds
そよ吹く髪
Hair blowing in the breeze
その枝を
That branch
知ってるよ
I know
あたしたちフードマジックお見せしたい
We want to show you some food magic
ハイテックな一挙手一投足
Every single high-tech move
戻したい 戻したい 持ちたい 狂いちゃいなら
I want to go back, want to go back, want to hold on, if I'm going crazy
見せ見せとボタンポチ
Show me, show me, and press the button
見せ見せとなど好き
Show me, show me, and I like it or something
見せ見せとボタンポチ
Show me, show me, and press the button
あずひしめけ スリトスラーカスオータス
Azu hi shimeke sutosu rakasupasu...
いさいからウェイストタイムまでのぼりだから
Since it's an uphill climb from the details to waste time
もちもちきりやさしくぶっとばす
Gently blow away the chewy items
めつのマイル ねんねんころね Oh yeah
The final mile, sleep well Korone, Oh yeah
Oh yeah!
It's the one me
おすかーかーぴょんへー
Osu ka ka pyon he
Oh yeah!
True the valley
オリコに迷ってる
Lost in the orico
Wow Wow Loud and down わさりまわさ
Wow Wow Loud and down...
Wow Wow Loud and down ふるなこの生き様
Wow Wow Loud and down, this way of life
掴んだら離さない ワンチャンスで輝く
Once grabbed, don't let go, shine with one chance
甘えて適当キャラ 孤独抱き
Being spoiled and a casual character, holding loneliness
おげおげ！ 僕が君の神様になったげる
Oge oge! I'll become your god
あーねいいじゃん うんうんえらい
Ah, that's good, yeah, you're doing great
おー完璧 チャーマイスカレ
Oh, perfect, super my-pace
グッド！ 結構！ 肯定！ 肯定！
Good! Great! Affirmation! Affirmation!
さすがっし 自信持って これね！
As expected, have confidence in this!
素晴らしい世界 地そばにいるよ
A wonderful world, I'm right by your side
大好き 超好き つまり好き
I love you, super love you, basically love you
いいよ当然！ なんとかなるよ！
Of course it's fine! Everything will be alright!
にっこりぬくぬく 猫可愛がり！
Smiling and warm, doting like a cat!
君もレッツ！ からめて！
You too, let's! Mix it in!
いいじゃんいいじゃん すごいじゃん
That's good, that's good, you're amazing
（すごい！）
(Amazing!)
いいじゃんいいじゃん えらいちゃん
That's good, that's good, you're a good kid
（えらい！）
(Great!)
そうでしょうそうでしょう もっと僕のそばにおいでよ
Right? Right? Come closer to me
前肯定！
Total affirmation!
いいじゃんいいじゃん すごいじゃん
That's good, that's good, you're amazing
（すごい！）
(Amazing!)
いいじゃんいいじゃん えらいちゃん
That's good, that's good, you're a good kid
（えらい！）
(Great!)
おげおげ！ 僕が君の神様になったげる
Oge oge! I'll become your god
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare pare pare, we're going to shine
呼び合うこれを合図に
Using this mutual call as a signal
パレパレパレ 探しに行く
Pare pare pare, we're going to search
ずっと何度だって
Forever, over and over again
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare pare pare, we're going to shine
暗闇を満たすのは 君だ僕だ
The one who fills the darkness is you and me
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Pare pare pare, we're going to shine
悔しさも愛おしさも 連れておいで
Bring along the frustration and the loveliness
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight
ささやかな祈り光 終わりなき日差し
A modest prayer of light, endless sunshine
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵なステージさ
Diving in with you, it's a wonderful stage
ここからこれから アワーブライト
From here on out, our bright
パレパレ
Pare pare
ハピチョコ
Hapi Choco
作詞・作曲・編曲：ヤマモトショウ
Lyrics/Composition/Arrangement: Sho Yamamoto
Happy New Year そろそろ考えなくちゃ
Happy New Year, it's about time I start thinking
みんながちょっとうるさいし まずは作戦会議
Everyone's being a bit noisy, so let's have a strategy meeting first
あけおめ！今から始まるラブストーリーとか？
Happy New Year! Maybe a love story starting now?
そんなんじゃないし 本命は私
It's nothing like that, I'm the one they really like
今日が本番だっていうの？
You say today is the big day?
大事なのはここから1ヶ月 じらしたいな
What's important is the month from now, I want to keep them waiting
大人になったって ドキドキしてたいもん だって
Even when I'm an adult, I still want to feel my heart racing because...
両思いの先払いに
In advance of our mutual love
うんと
A lot
甘い甘い甘い甘い 甘いの好き好き好き好き
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, I love, love, love, love sweets
っていう私が選んだ君は とびきりのスイート
That's what I said, and the one I chose is you, the sweetest of all
甘い甘い甘い甘い 一年で
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, in a year
一番の贅沢でも しちゃいましょうよ
Let's have the biggest luxury of all
チョチョチョトチョコあとは
Cho-cho-cho-choco, and then
予算とカロリーとかオーバーでもね あーあ
Even if we go over budget and calories, oh well
チョチョチョトチョコレート
Cho-cho-cho-chocolate
私の恋とかにご褒美あげたい
I want to give a reward to my love or something
もう今日だって会いたいわ 決めました
I've decided I want to see you even today
お宅用ですか？って なんでわかったの
Is it for home use? How did you know?
そうでもやっぱ みんなそわそわしちゃうの
Still, everyone ends up getting restless
そりゃそうだけどね よそ見したらそれも変かな
Well, that's true, but would it be weird to look away too?
ねぇ 呼び出しなんて なになに
Hey, what's with the summoning?
今のところは 帰って楽しみたかったのにな
I was looking forward to going home and enjoying myself for now
でもあれ 私が欲しかった可愛いやつじゃない
But isn't that the cute thing I wanted?
気になるこれ片想い
It's on my mind, this unrequited love
でもっと
And more
甘い甘い甘い甘い 甘いの好き好き好き好き
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, I love, love, love, love sweets
そんな私にあなたがくれた とびきりのサプライズ
For someone like me, you gave me the biggest surprise
やばいやばいやばいやばい そんなこと
Oh no, oh no, oh no, oh no, that kind of thing
想像もしてなかったの 眠れないね
I hadn't even imagined it, I can't sleep
1ヶ月も悩むなんて
Worrying for a whole month
そんなの無理じゃない？
Isn't that impossible?
私毎日が 本命全力
Every day for me is full effort for the one I love
そういうのが好きでごめん
Sorry for liking that kind of thing
うんと
A lot
甘い甘い甘い甘い 甘いの好き好き好き好き
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, I love, love, love, love sweets
っていう私が選んだ君は とびきりのスイート
That's what I said, and the one I chose is you, the sweetest of all
甘い甘い甘い甘い 一年で
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, in a year
一番の贅沢でもしよう
Let's have the biggest luxury of all
うんと
A lot
甘い甘い甘い甘い 甘いの好き好き好き好き
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, I love, love, love, love sweets
っていう私が選んだ君は とびきりのスイート
That's what I said, and the one I chose is you, the sweetest of all
甘い甘い甘い甘い 一年で
Sweet, sweet, sweet, sweet, in a year
一番の贅沢でも しちゃいましょうよ
Let's have the biggest luxury of all
チョチョチョトチョコあとは
Cho-cho-cho-choco, and then
予算とカロリーとかオーバーでもね あーあ
Even if we go over budget and calories, oh well
チョチョチョトチョコレート
Cho-cho-cho-chocolate
私の恋とかにご褒美あげたい
I want to give a reward to my love or something
私の今日からにご褒美あげたい
I want to give a reward starting from my today
みんなできたー！？
Everyone, did you manage to do it!?
まだまだ...
Not yet...
まだあるからね！
There's still more!
次はチームBで... SHOWTIME ROLLER!
Next is Team B with... SHOWTIME ROLLER!
落ちてゆくシャンデリア
A falling chandelier
痛みに火を灯すネオンライト
Neon lights that ignite the pain
Four, five, six 鳴らせ Clap
Four, five, six, make it clap
スポットライト浴びて
Bathed in the spotlight
さあ、ようこそ　ベアトリーチェ　開演さ　イッツショータイム
Come now, welcome Beatrice, it's curtain time, it's showtime
ショウタイム・ルーラー
作詞・作曲：鳥屋茶房
Showtime Ruler
Lyrics/Composition: Toriya Sabou
たらった　踊るステップ踏んで
Taratta, with dancing steps
流動し　せわしない鼓動
A restless, flowing pulse
急転直下　心臓はチックタックほら
A sudden plunge, my heart goes tick-tock, see?
キューアンドエー
Q&A
アクション
Action
Seven, eight 溢れてく
Seven, eight, it's overflowing
悩んで　青を帯びていく
Worrying, it takes on a blue hue
緊張感を解き放つ頃
Just as the tension is released
一瞬へ　さあショータイム
To this moment, now, showtime!
Amp up...
僕の感性を　Amp up　更新中
Amping up my sensitivity, currently updating
君の感性に　Amp up　挑戦中
Amping up your sensitivity, currently challenging
研ぎ澄ませ　Amp up　この一瞬
Amp up, sharpen it, Amp up this moment
君の感情の　支配者さ　ショウタイム
Amp up, I'm the ruler of your emotions, showtime
ラララララ...
La la la la la...
It's showtime!
Higher, higher, higher!
Crazy, crazy, crazyにしちゃって
Make it crazy, crazy, crazy
Once again!
ラララララ...
La la la la la...
It's showtime!
Higher, higher, higher!
自由に　自由に　自由に　ショウタイム
Freely, freely, freely, showtime
夢みたいな時間
A dreamlike time
さあもっと声を聴かせて頂戴な
Now, please let me hear your voices more
沸き上がる感情の共鳴が
The resonance of surging emotions
君を飲み込んでさ
Swallows you up
僕を飲み込んでさ
Swallows me up
天も不満も歓喜も
Heaven, dissatisfaction, and joy
僕の思い通り
Everything as I please
二度と孤独になんてなれないよ
You'll never be lonely again
More crazy!
僕の合図で
At my signal
More crazy!
君は合図ステージ
You're at the signal stage
ショウタイム
Showtime
今、一つになって
Now, becoming one
会場に響く喝采
The applause echoing in the venue
毎秒描き出す世界で
In a world we create every second
段上から揺さぶる歓声
Cheers shaking the stage
泣きそうなほどに重なって
Overlapping so much it almost makes me cry
本気の愛楽　Under control
True joy and sorrow, under control
今　僕らの思いを　乱舞
Now, our feelings dance wildly
君の鼓動　そいつがショウタイム
Your heartbeat, that's showtime
そう僕らを繋ぐよ　ショウタイム
Yes, it connects us, showtime
ラララララ...
La la la la la...
夢みたいな時間
A dreamlike time
It's showtime!
More crazy!
みなさん！
Everyone!
楽しめましたかー！？
Did you have fun!?
ちょっとね...
Well...
みんな、疲れてると思うけど...
I think everyone's tired, but...
あと一曲あります！
We have one more song!
はい！
Yes!
最後の曲は、ホロライブ・プロジェクト全員で...
The last song is, with all of Hololive Project...
MY舞☆TONIGHT！
MY MAI TONIGHT!
踊れ！踊れ！
Dance! Dance!
熱くなるため
To get fired up
人は生まれてきたはずさ
People were born for this
MY舞☆TONIGHT
作詞：畑 亜貴 / 作曲・編曲：EFFY
MY MAI TONIGHT
Lyrics: Aki Hata / Composition & Arrangement: EFFY
今　小さく燃えてる
Now, burning small
まだ小さな火の粉が
Still a small spark
一つになれば
If they become one
奇跡が生まれる
A miracle will be born
この世界はいつも
This world always
諦めない心に
To the heart that doesn't give up
答えじゃなく
Not an answer
道を探す
But looking for a path
手がかりをくれるから
Because it gives us clues
さあ！
Now!
最後まで強気で行こう
Let's go with confidence until the end
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
熱くなるため 人は生まれてきたの
To the point of getting hot, that's why people were born
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
きっとそうだよ だから夢見て踊ろう
I'm sure that's it, so let's dream and dance
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
最高の
The best
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
今日にしよう
Let's make it today
いつか広がるだろう
Someday it will spread
ほら大きく日の光
Look, the big sunlight
頑張る力
The power to work hard
奇跡を呼んでいる
Is calling for a miracle
この世界の中で
In this world
輝きたい心が集まる時
When hearts that want to shine gather
新しいこと思いつき走り出す
Coming up with something new and starting to run
足元が見えないけど
Even if I can't see my feet
羽みたいに手を伸ばして
Stretch out your hands like wings
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
憧れたのは ずっと瞬く光
What I yearned for was always the twinkling light
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
きっといつかは 叶うはずだと踊ろう
Let's dance thinking that it will surely come true someday
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
明日へと
To tomorrow
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
繋げよう
Let's connect
誰かの声に導かれて
Guided by someone's voice
道がまた開けたよ
The road has opened again
最後まで強気で行こう
Let's go with confidence until the end
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
熱くなるため 人は生まれてきたの
To the point of getting hot, that's why people were born
踊れ 踊れ
Dance, dance
きっとそうだよ だから夢見て踊ろう
I'm sure that's it, so let's dream and dance
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
最高の
The best
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
今日にしよう
Let's make it today
MY舞☆TONIGHT (DANCING TONIGHT)
せーの！
Ready, set...
ハッピーニューイヤー！
Happy New Year!
STAFF
エグゼクティブプロデューサー
谷郷元昭
Executive Producer
Motoaki Tanigo
企画・運営
Planning / Operation
ライブ演出
Live Staging
「hololive Shuffle Medley 2024」
“hololive Shuffle Medley 2024”
SPECIAL THANKS
ホロライブを応援してくれている皆様
To everyone who supports hololive
ゆくホロ2023！
くるホロ2024！
Holo 2023 goes!
Holo 2024 comes!
2タイトル好評販売中！
2 titles on sale now!
いろはにまったりお正月
Iroha ni Mattari Oshougatsu
2024年1月1日 13:00より
From Jan 1, 2024 at 13:00
ホロライブ公式chにて配信スタート！
Streaming starts on hololive official ch!
夢を指した 君じゃ無理
Pointing at a dream, "it's impossible for you"
立ちすくんだ 真っ暗闇で
Standing still in the pitch black darkness
怖かった 怖かった
It was scary, it was scary
照らしてくれたのは
The one who lit my way...
スターライト みんなの光
Starlight, everyone's light
スターライト これが僕の光
Starlight, this is my light
ホロプラス！
holoplus!
ライブ、最高でしたね。
The live was amazing!
感想をホロプラスに投稿っと。
I'll post my thoughts on holoplus.
あ、
Oh,
あけましておめでとうございます！
Happy New Year!
ホロプラス宣伝隊長の春先のどかです！
I'm Harusaki Nodaka, the holoplus promotion manager!
公式アプリ「ホロプラス」では
On the official app “holoplus,”
カウントダウンライブ連動キャンペーンを開催中！
a countdown live collab campaign is underway!
推し活するだけでプレゼントが当たるチャンス…！？
A chance to win prizes just by supporting your oshi...!?
詳しくは「ホロプラス」をチェック！
Check “holoplus” for details!
2024年も「ホロプラス」をよろしくお願いいたします！
Please continue to support “holoplus” in 2024!
おつホロプラス〜！
Otsu-holoplus~!
綺麗じゃない 綺麗じゃない でも
It's not beautiful, it's not beautiful, but
嫌いじゃない 嫌いじゃないでしょう
I don't hate it, I don't hate it, right?
まっすぐに不器用でもいい
It's okay to be straightforwardly clumsy
どうでもいい どうでもいいんだよ
It doesn't matter, it doesn't matter
君を襲うどんな雨も
Whatever rain attacks you
水たまり踏みつけて
Step through the puddles
笑われたっていいんだ
It's fine even if you're laughed at
Moona Hoshinova
ORBITURE
01. 愛の小さな歌
02. High Tide
01. Ai no Chiisana Uta
Shiori Novella
Koseki Bijou
Nerissa Ravencroft
Fuwawa Abyssgard
Mococo Abyssgard
正月衣装 お披露目リレー配信
2024年 1月1日(JST)
New Year's Outfit Reveal Relay Stream
Jan 1, 2024 (JST)
こんこんきつねー！
Kon kon kitsune!
ふわふわしっぽの五番星、
The fifth star with a fluffy tail,
あなたの心の一番推し、白上フブキです！
your heart's number one favorite, Shirakami Fubuki here!
Hi friends!
皆さん、速報じゃい！
Everyone, I've got breaking news!
来る2024年1月5日に、
On this upcoming January 5, 2024,
周防パトラちゃんと3Dコラボ配信が決定しました！イエーイ！
a 3D collaboration stream with Suou Patra has been confirmed! Yay!
1月5日は白上チャンネルで行いますので、皆さんお楽しみに！
It'll be on the Shirakami Channel on Jan 5, so please look forward to it!
では最後に、パトラちゃんから一言！
And finally, a word from Patra-chan!
こんぱんわんわー！
Kon-ban-wa-wa!
周防パトラです！
I'm Suou Patra!
1月5日、ホロライブスタジオに遊びに行っちゃうよ！
I'm coming over to the Hololive Studio on January 5th!
皆さん、よろしくお願いします！
Everyone, nice to meet you!
hololive production
COUNTDOWN LIVE 2023▷2024
-hololive side-